A comedy about fear of commitment, hating your job,
falling in love and other pop favorites.
High Fidelity is a drama, comedy, romance film directed by Stephen Frears.
After his long-time girlfriend dumps him, a thirty-year-old record store owner seeks to understand
why he is unlucky in love while recounting his "top five breakups of all time".
Rob Gordon, played by John Cusack.
Laura, played by Iben Hjejle.
Dick, played by Todd Louiso.
Barry Judd, played by Jack Black.
Marie DeSalle, played by Lisa Bonet.
Charlie Nicholson, played by Catherine Zeta-Jones.
High Fidelity is a 2000 romantic comedy-drama film directed by Stephen Frears and starring John Cusack alongside an ensemble cast of Jack
Black, Lisa Bonet, Joelle Carter, Joan Cusack, Sara Gilbert, Iben Hjejle, Todd Louiso, Lili Taylor, and Natasha Gregson Wagner.
Based on the 1995 novel of the same name by Nick Hornby, with the setting moved from London to Chicago and the protagonist's name changed, the film follows Rob Gordon (Cusack), a
record store owner who is recently single after a breakup with Laura (Hjejle), leading him to look back on his worst five breakups while attempting to reconcile with her.
Hornby expressed surprise at how faithful the adaptation was, saying "at times, it appears to be a film in which John Cusack reads my book."
Released theatrically in the United States by Buena Vista
Pictures Distribution on March 31, 2000, High Fidelity grossed $47.1 million worldwide and received highly positive reviews from critics, who praised the cast's performances and Frears' direction.
Cusack was nominated for a Golden Globe Award for Best
Actor – Motion Picture Musical or Comedy.
A television series of the same name based off of the film and
novel was released on Hulu on February 14, 2020.
The series starred Zoë Kravitz, Bonet's daughter, in the role of Rob.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, rock 'n'
roll, music record, disc jockey, pop.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.